Frank Jasek papers, Inclusive: 1915-2012, undated, Bulk: 1939-2012, undated
Baylor University, The Texas Collection
Frank Jasek papers
Inclusive: 1915-2012, undated, Bulk: 1939-2012, undated
Baylor University, The Texas Collection http://www.baylor.edu/lib/texas/
3932
Jasek, Frank
19 document boxes.
The Frank Jasek papers contain research filesDLconsisting mostly of notes, correspondence, photographs, compact discs, and literary productionsDLused in the publication of Soldiers of the Wooden Cross: Military Memorials of Baylor University.
Administrative Information
Physical Description
General condition: Good.
Biography/Profile
Frank Jasek, born in 1947, authored the book Soldiers of the Wooden Cross: Military Memorials of Baylor University. He graduated from Southeastern University in 1969 with an aviation degree, and from Baylor University with a business administration degree in 1973. He married Janet Jasek in 1978. Frank Jasek worked at Moody Memorial Library at Baylor University starting in 1996.
After eleven years of research, he self-published Soldiers of the Wooden Cross: Military Memorials of Baylor University in 2012. The project involved writing about Baylor alumni who died as a member of the military forces of the United States. Each deceased alumni is represented on Baylor campus by a granite lamppost, with their name inscribed on a plaque attached to the lamppost. Their stories are preserved in the book, along with photographs of them as available.
Scope and Content
The Frank Jasek papers begin in 1915 and end in 2012. The largest series in the collection is the Soldiers of the Wooden Cross, Baylor University Memorial Lamppost Plaques series, which contains Jasek’s subject files used in compiling the majority of his book. The only other series in the collectionDL Soldiers of the Wooden Cross, Research FilesDLconsists of various supplementary items also used in completing the volume.
The Frank Jasek papers contain many of the subject and research files used by Jasek in writing and compiling his edited volume of short biographies, Soldiers of the Wooden Cross: Military Memorials of Baylor University. This book identifies and outlines the lives of Baylor men and women who died while serving in the armed forces. These individuals have been memorialized on the campus of Baylor University through the erection of lampposts with shield-shaped plaques bearing their names. The first eighty-four lampposts were built in 1946, with at least sixty more that have been added since.
Arrangement
When the collection was donated, most of the files were organized alphabetically by folder title. The few that were out of sequence have been placed in their proper order to reflect an alphabetical arrangement. Since the folders already had titles when the collection was donated, existing folder titles have been preserved. When the spelling of names from folder titles did not match names that appeared in Soldiers of the Wooden Cross, the spelling used in the book has been provided in brackets as part of the folder title.
An inventory was created shortly after the collection was donated but prior to the creation of this finding aid.
The collection is currently organized into two series: I. Soldiers of the Wooden Cross, Baylor University Memorial Lamppost Plaques, II. Soldiers of the Wooden Cross, Research Files.
Access Restrictions
All requests for copying of materials must be submitted to The Texas Collection in writing. Please use the Request Form for Copying Materials sheet. Unpublished materials authored or otherwise produced by the creator (s) of this collection are in the public domain. There are no restrictions on use. Copyright status for other collection materials is unknown. Transmission or reproduction of materials protected by U.S. Copyright Law (Title 17, U.S.C.) beyond that allowed by fair use requires the written permission of the copyright owners. Works not in the public domain cannot be commercially exploited without permission of the copyright owners. Responsibility for any use rests exclusively with the user.
Acquisition Information
Accession No. 3932. Acquired 2013-06-03
Related Resources
Related references
Baylor University. “Trees, Benches & Lamp Posts.” University Development. Accessed 2013 September 24.
"Getting to KnowELFrank Jasek ’73." Baylor Line Foundation, May 26, 2016. Accessed 2020 May 6.
Jasek, Frank, ed. Soldiers of the Wooden Cross: Military Memorials of Baylor University. [Waco, TX?: Frank Jasek?], 2012.
Stockton, James. “Lampposts represent sacrifice of Baylor military men and women.” Baylor Lariat (Waco, TX), 2011 January 28. Accessed 2013 September 24.
Webmaster. “Book preserver publishes stories about fallen soldiers, alumni.” Baylor Lariat (Waco, TX), 2013 November 22. Accessed 2020 May 6.
Index Terms
Subjects (Organizations)
Baylor University -- History, Military.; Baylor University -- Students -- Biography.
Places
United States -- Armed Forces -- Texas -- Biography.
Subjects
Compact discs.; Correspondence.; Inscriptions -- Texas -- Waco.; Photographs.; Plaques, plaquettes -- Texas -- Waco.; Research notes.; Soldiers -- Texas -- Biography.; War Memorials -- Texas -- Waco.
- Soldiers of the Wooden Cross, Baylor University Memorial Lamppost Plaques, 1923-2012, undated; 1
  Administrative Information
  Physical Description
  General condition: Good.
  Biography/Profile
  This series contains subject and research files used in compiling histories of individuals discussed in Soldiers of the Wooden Cross.
  Index Terms
  Genres
  Compact disk (CD); Photographic print
  - Attebury, Eugene T. [Atteberry, Eugene T.], 1941-2008, undated (Box 1, Folder 1)
  - Bagwell, Frank, Jr., 2004-2009, undated (Box 1, Folder 2)
  - Bailes, Joe Dean, 1953-2012, undated (Box 1, Folder 3)
  - Bankston, Buell A., 2004-2010, undated (Box 1, Folder 4)
  - Barnett, Marshall D., Jr., 1941-2008, undated (Box 1, Folder 5)
  - Bates, Pauline [Bates, Pauline O.], 1935-2008, undated (Box 1, Folder 6)
  - Bell, Alfred H. [Bell, Alfred Harris], 1988-2010, undated (Box 1, Folder 7)
  - Bennett, Horace Dan (Jack), 1945-2010, undated (Box 1, Folder 8)
  - Black, Lester T. [Black, Lester L.], 1945-2012, undated (Box 1, Folder 9)
  - Boggess, Robert Woodfin, Jr., 1904-2011, undated (Box 1, Folder 10)
  - Brock, Harold Paul, 2005-2010, undated (Box 1, Folder 11)
  - Brown, Cynthia [Brown, Cynthia Campbell], 1995-2012, undated (Box 1, Folder 12)
  - Bruner, Benajha [Bruner, Benajha Harvey "Ben," Jr.], 1944-2008, undated (Box 2, Folder 1)
  - Bruner, Benajha [Bruner, Benajha Harvey "Ben," Jr.]: Photographs, 1939-1945, undated (Box 2, Folder 2)
  - Brunson, W. T. [Brunson, Wade T.], 1945-2008, undated (Box 2, Folder 3)
  - Bryan, Billy Batte, 1944-2005, undated (Box 2, Folder 4)
  - Bryski, Frank, 1939-2012, undated (Box 2, Folder 5)
  - Byrd, Joe Curtis, Jr., 1941-2012, undated (Box 2, Folder 6)
  - Byrn, John Bussey, 1942-2010, undated (Box 2, Folder 7)
  - Casey, Jack Allen, 1941-2012, undated (Box 2, Folder 8)
  - Chadwick, James Woodrow (1 of 2), 1944-2008, undated (Box 2, Folder 9)
  - Chadwick, James Woodrow (2 of 2), 1944-2008, undated (Box 2, Folder 10)
  - Cheavens, Tom H. [Cheavens, Thomas Henry], 1923-2008, undated (Box 3, Folder 1)
  - Childers, William A., Jr. [Childers, William Arthur, Jr.], 1944-2008, undated (Box 3, Folder 2)
  - Colley, Lionel DeWitt, 1941-2008, undated (Box 3, Folder 3)
  - Cornelius, John Milton, 1945-2005, undated (Box 3, Folder 4)
  - Cowan, John David, 1941-2008, undated (Box 3, Folder 5)
  - Cox, Frank T., Jr., 1944-2008, undated (Box 3, Folder 6)
  - Cox, Frank [Cox, Frank T., Jr.] IDPF File (1 of 2), 1945-2008, undated (Box 3, Folder 7)
  - Cox, Frank [Cox, Frank T., Jr.] IDPF File (2 of 2), 1945-2008, undated (Box 3, Folder 8)
  - Crawford, Robert A., 1944-2010, undated (Box 3, Folder 9)
  - Crouch, Loren Bailey, 1941-2010, undated (Box 3, Folder 10)
  - Cundiff, Dale [Cundiff, Herbert Dale], 1942-2010, undated (Box 3, Folder 11)
  - Cunningham, Donald Maurice, 1942-2004, undated (Box 3, Folder 12)
  - Dale, Kerry [Dale, Kerry Duane], 1988-2012, undated (Box 4, Folder 1)
  - Dalton, Lowell Aynesworth (1 of 2), 1941-2008, undated (Box 4, Folder 2)
  - Dalton, Lowell Aynesworth (2 of 2), 1941-2008, undated (Box 4, Folder 3)
  - Dalton [Dalton, Lowell Aynesworth]: Resume/Work Experience, 1942-2004, undated (Box 4, Folder 4)
  - Dalton [Dalton, Lowell Aynesworth]: Fitness Reports, 1942-1944 (Box 4, Folder 5)
  - Dalton [Dalton, Lowell Aynesworth]: Unit History: 4th Marine Division, 2008 (Box 4, Folder 6)
  - Dalton [Dalton, Lowell Aynesworth]: Notes: Manuscript, undated (Box 4, Folder 7)
  - Dalton [Dalton, Lowell Aynesworth]: Death Certificate and Insurance, 1943-2010, undated (Box 4, Folder 8)
  - Dalton [Dalton, Lowell Aynesworth]: Service Record, 1942-1950, undated (Box 4, Folder 9)
  - Daniel, Robert Houston, Jr., 1941-2006, undated (Box 4, Folder 10)
  - Day, Morris Eugene, 1945-2012, undated (Box 4, Folder 11)
  - Dean, John Mack, 1969-2008, undated (Box 4, Folder 12)
  - Deter, Dwight M., 1944-2011, undated (Box 4, Folder 13)
  - Dewlen, Michael Lee, 1969-2008, undated (Box 5, Folder 1)
  - Douglas, Lowell N. [Douglas, Lowell Newton], 1937-2008, undated (Box 5, Folder 2)
  - Edens, Alfred G. [Edens, Alfred Grady, Jr.], 1943-2008, undated (Box 5, Folder 3)
  - Edgar, William Silver, 1942-2010, undated (Box 5, Folder 4)
  - [Edgar, William Silver]: "Wing Across the World", 1940 (Box 5, Folder 5)
  - Eilenberger, Louis G., Jr., 1945-2008, undated (Box 5, Folder 6)
  - Elliot, Conord, 1943-2011, undated (Box 5, Folder 7)
  - Elliott, Willie Wilfrea, 1941-2012, undated (Box 5, Folder 8)
  - Englander, A. J. [Englander, Asher Joseph Jem], 2004-2009, undated (Box 5, Folder 9)
  - Evans, James Rufus, 1943-2010, undated (Box 5, Folder 10)
  - Fielder, Wilson, Jr., 1950-2008, undated (Box 5, Folder 11)
  - Fielder, Wilson, Jr.: Photographs, undated (Box 5, Folder 12)
  - Finley, Charles Wilson, 1945-2010, undated (Box 5, Folder 13)
  - Fisher, Raymond L., 1944-2006, undated (Box 6, Folder 1)
  - Florey, Ralph [Florey, Ralph N., Jr.], 1945-2012, undated (Box 6, Folder 2)
  - Fordham, Benjamin Stephen [Fordham, Benjamin Steve], 1998-2010, undated (Box 6, Folder 3)
  - Foster, Edwin W., III, 2005-2010, undated (Box 6, Folder 4)
  - Fox, Robert E. [Fox, Robert Earle], 1939-2008, undated (Box 6, Folder 5)
  - Frey, Henry Counts, 1983-2008, undated (Box 6, Folder 6)
  - Galbraith, James Newton, 1941-2008, undated (Box 6, Folder 7)
  - Gernand, Walter Davis, 1944-2008, undated (Box 6, Folder 8)
  - Gibson, Edward F. [Gibson, Edward Frederick], 2004-2009, undated (Box 6, Folder 9)
  - Gilmore, Lester [Gilmore, Lester T.], 1945-2008, undated (Box 6, Folder 10)
  - Godbold, W. B., Jr. [Godbold, William B., Jr.], 1941-2008, undated (Box 6, Folder 11)
  - Goldsmith, Oliver Joseph, 1942-2008, undated (Box 6, Folder 12)
  - Griffiths, Charles C., Jr. [Griffiths, Charles Clayton, Jr.], 1945-2008, undated (Box 7, Folder 1)
  - Groce, Billy Bob, 1943-2009, undated (Box 7, Folder 2)
  - Hale, William [Hale, William Thomas], 2000-2008, undated (Box 7, Folder 3)
  - Hamilton, James S. [Hamilton, James Scott], 1944-2008, undated (Box 7, Folder 4)
  - Hanna, John Dwight (Jack), 1943-2008, undated (Box 7, Folder 5)
  - Harris, Charles J., 1942-2008, undated (Box 7, Folder 6)
  - Harris, Joshua C., Jr., 1955-2008, undated (Box 7, Folder 7)
  - Hawkins, H. Ray [Hawkins, Hartwell Ray] (1 of 2), 1942-2012, undated (Box 7, Folder 8)
  - Hawkins, H. Ray [Hawkins, Hartwell Ray] (2 of 2), 1942-2012, undated (Folder 9)
  - Healy, Charles F. [Healy, Charles Fortran], 1942-2008, undated (Box 7, Folder 10)
  - Heard, John Jesse, 1942-2010, undated (Box 7, Folder 11)
  - Hendricks, Lucille, 1944-2011, undated (Box 8, Folder 1)
  - Hill, Fred Walter [Hill, Walter Fred], 1934-2010, undated (Box 8, Folder 2)
  - Hinds, Donald Paul (1 of 2), 1941-2004, undated (Box 8, Folder 3)
  - Hinds, Donald Paul (2 of 2), 1941-2004, undated (Box 8, Folder 4)
  - Hogg, Ross, 1926-2010, undated (Box 8, Folder 5)
  - Hornbuckle, Paul R., 1945-2010, undated (Box 8, Folder 6)
  - Johnson, Wilbur Leslie, 1996-2008, undated (Box 8, Folder 7)
  - Kelly, Elvis L., 1943-2008, undated (Box 8, Folder 8)
  - Kenny, Earl W. [Kenny, Earl Wright], 1943-2010, undated (Box 8, Folder 9)
  - Lambert, H. B., Jr. [Lambert, Herman Burton, Jr.], 1937-2008, undated (Box 8, Folder 10)
  - Landers, Alden L., 1943-2010, undated (Box 9, Folder 1)
  - Latimer, R. E., Jr. [Latimer, Richard E., Jr.], 2004-2007, undated (Box 9, Folder 2)
  - Lawrence, John Galen, 1945-2007, undated (Box 9, Folder 3)
  - Lawson, William L. [Lawson, William Lawrence, Jr.], 1943-2009, undated (Box 9, Folder 4)
  - Lawton, Harry, 1943-2012, undated (Box 9, Folder 5)
  - Lindsey, James Rex, 1944-2008, undated (Box 9, Folder 6)
  - Lummus, Jack [Lummus, Andrew Jackson "Jack," Jr.], 1944-2012, undated (Box 9, Folder 7)
  - Madden, Henry Otto (1 of 2), 1942-2008, undated (Box 9, Folder 8)
  - Madden, Henry Otto (2 of 2), 1942-2008, undated (Box 9, Folder 9)
  - Mallory, Charles Hays, 1943-2008, undated (Box 9, Folder 10)
  - Marmar, Aaron Charles, 2004-2012, undated (Box 9, Folder 11)
  - Maros, Phil, 1945-2012, undated (Box 10, Folder 1)
  - Mason, Walter Phillip, Jr., 1943-2009, undated (Box 10, Folder 2)
  - McAda, Oscar David, 1943-2008, undated (Box 10, Folder 3)
  - McAda, Oscar David: Photographs, undated (Box 10, Folder 4)
  - McAdoo, Robert L., 1942-2010, undated (Box 10, Folder 5)
  - McCreary, Joseph S. [McCreary, Joseph Samuel], 1943-2008, undated (Box 10, Folder 6)
  - McCreary, Joseph S. [McCreary, Joseph Samuel]: Photographs, 1944, undated (Box 10, Folder 7)
  - McCreary [McCreary, Joseph Samuel] (1 of 2), 1943-2007, undated (Box 10, Folder 8)
  - McCreary [McCreary, Joseph Samuel] (2 of 2), 1943-2007, undated (Box 10, Folder 9)
  - Middlebrook, Carl L., Jr. [Middlebrook, Carl Lovelace, Jr.], 1945-2008, undated (Box 10, Folder 10)
  - Middleton, Evelyn Maureen, 1944-2006, undated (Box 10, Folder 11)
  - Milam, Robert Cameron, 1944-2009, undated (Box 10, Folder 12)
  - Minton, Joseph O., 1946-2009, undated (Box 11, Folder 1)
  - Moore, James [Moore, James Edwin], 1942-2008, undated (Box 11, Folder 2)
  - Moore, Weston L., 1943-2010, undated (Box 11, Folder 3)
  - Morgan, Lowell E., 1966-2009, undated (Box 11, Folder 4)
  - Murry [Murray, Billy Jim] (1 of 2), 1943-2009, undated (Box 11, Folder 5)
  - Murry [Murray, Billy Jim] (2 of 2), 1943-2009, undated (Box 11, Folder 6)
  - Myers, Henry Arthur [Myers, Henry Arthur, Jr.], 1942-2006, undated (Box 11, Folder 7)
  - Nalley, Wm. Fred [Nalley, William Fred], 1944-2011, undated (Box 11, Folder 8)
  - Neff, Merlin S. [Neff, Merlin Shepherd], 1941-2009, undated (Box 11, Folder 9)
  - Nelson, James B., 1945-2005, undated (Box 11, Folder 10)
  - Orlando [Orlando, Kim S.], 2011, undated (Box 11, Folder 11)
  - Parker, Carroll Bruton, 1944-2004, undated (Box 11, Folder 12)
  - Parks, Mitchell Lee, 1937-2009, undated (Box 11, Folder 13)
  - Peacock, Harry Jennings, 1944-2012, undated (Box 12, Folder 1)
  - Pearce, William L., 1944-2009, undated (Box 11, Folder 13)
  - Pierce, Charles St. George, 1942-2012, undated (Box 12, Folder 1)
  - Pierce, Marion M. [Pierce, Marion McGinty], 2004-2011, undated (Box 12, Folder 2)
  - Pitts, Larry Glenn, 2004-2009, undated (Box 12, Folder 3)
  - Porter, Winston [Porter, Winston Sumter], 1941-2009, undated (Box 12, Folder 4)
  - Ricks, N. H. Youngblood, 1944-2010, undated (Box 12, Folder 5)
  - Riley, Edgar D. [Riley, Edgar David], 1943-2006, undated (Box 12, Folder 6)
  - Robbins, Robert L. [Robbins, Robert Lee], 1944-2012, undated (Box 12, Folder 7)
  - Robertson, Roy C., Jr. [Robertson, Roy Calvin, Jr.], 1939-2012, undated (Box 12, Folder 8)
  - Rogers, Curtis [Rogers, Curtis, Jr.], 2000-2007, undated (Box 12, Folder 9)
  - Ryon, John W. [Ryon, John William], 1953-2010, undated (Box 12, Folder 10)
  - Ryon, J. W. [Ryon, John William]: Letters Home, 1952-1971, undated (Box 12, Folder 11)
  - Ryon [Ryon, John William], File Sent to Warren Carah (1 of 2), 1953-2007, undated (Box 13, Folder 1)
  - Ryon [Ryon, John William], File Sent to Warren Carah (2 of 2), 1953-2007, undated (Box 13, Folder 2)
  - Ryon, J. W. [Ryon, John William]: Notes, 2007, undated (Box 13, Folder 3)
  - Ryon, J. W. [Ryon, John William]: Thailand Accident, 2007 (Box 13, Folder 4)
  - Ryon, J. W. [Ryon, John William]: EC-47 Story, 2007 (Box 13, Folder 5)
  - Ryon, J. W. [Ryon, John William]: Photos, undated (Box 13, Folder 6)
  - Sanders, Marshall Neill [Sanders, Marshall Neil], 1995-2012, undated (Box 13, Folder 7)
  - Sandlin, Grady, 2003-2007, undated (Box 13, Folder 8)
  - Schrader, Hugh (Chinky), Jr., 1945-2010, undated (Box 13, Folder 9)
  - Simms, Joseph Harold, 1945-2012, undated (Box 13, Folder 10)
  - Smith, Clinton E., Jr. (1 of 2), 1945-2012, undated (Box 13, Folder 11)
  - Smith, Clinton E., Jr. (2 of 2), 1945-2012, undated (Box 13, Folder 12)
  - Smith, Stanley Dean, 1945-2006, undated (Box 13, Folder 13)
  - Sparkman, Luther Henry, 1943-2012, undated (Box 14, Folder 1)
  - Spillman, James Elmore, 1941-2012, undated (Box 14, Folder 2)
  - Stout, John A. [Stout, John A., Jr.], 1945-2012, undated (Box 14, Folder 3)
  - Strum, George E., 1930-2012, undated (Box 14, Folder 4)
  - Summerhill, John Thomas, Jr., 1942-2007, undated (Box 14, Folder 5)
  - Talbott, Charles B. [Talbott, Charles Blakely], 1941-2012, undated (Box 14, Folder 6)
  - Tate, Tipton Oren [Tate, Tipton Orren, Jr.], 1943-2012, undated (Box 14, Folder 7)
  - Taylor, Joseph T., 1944-2009, undated (Box 14, Folder 8)
  - Turner, Vester L., 1943-2012, undated (Box 14, Folder 9)
  - Wallis, Charles Gordon, 1946-2009, undated (Box 14, Folder 10)
  - Warren, Robert Duncan [Warren, Robert Duncan, Jr.], 1943-2009, undated (Box 14, Folder 11)
  - Watts, Milledge H. [Watts, Milledge Hart], 1944-2009, undated (Box 15, Folder 1)
  - Waugh, C. W. [Waugh, Claude W., Jr.], 1942-2009, undated (Box 15, Folder 2)
  - Williams, Ernest H., 1945-2009, undated (Box 15, Folder 3)
  - Wilson, Ben Lawrence, 1945-2010, undated (Box 15, Folder 4)
  - Withers, Robert Levi, 1945-2009, undated (Box 15, Folder 5)
  - Wolf, Ralph R., Jr. [Wolf, Ralph Raymond, Jr.], 1946-2009, undated (Box 15, Folder 6)
  - Youngblood, Douglas [Youngblood, Douglas Richard], 1943-2009, undated (Box 15, Folder 7)
  - Zarr, Edgar F., 1944-2012, undated (Box 15, Folder 8)
- Soldiers of the Wooden Cross, Research Files, 1915-2011, undated; 2
  This series contains supplementary research files used in compiling Soldiers of the Wooden Cross.
  - American Civil War, 2002-2009, undated (Box 15, Folder 9)
  - [Baylor University Memorial Lamppost Plaques]: Plaque Revisions, 2009, undated (Box 15, Folder 10)
  - Martin, Anna: Wings Club Letters, 1942-2011, undated (Box 15, Folder 11)
  - Flat Hatting, 1990-2006, undated (Box 15, Folder 12)
  - Herbert, Raynor L.: Possible Future Plaque, 2008 (Box 15, Folder 13)
  - Hulls, Norman J., 1945-2008 (Box 15, Folder 14)
  - Dellinger, Paul and Gilbreath, James, 2007, undated (Box 15, Folder 15)
  - Caskey, Homer J., 1915-1953, undated (Box 16, Folder 1)
  - Price, Ruben C., 1946-2008, undated (Box 16, Folder 2)
  - Dubious, Travis, 2009, undated (Box 16, Folder 3)
  - Baylor University: Killed in World War II: The Baylor Line, 1946 (Box 16, Folder 4)
  - Baylor University: Killed in World War II: Old Ones: Plaques, 1946-1995 (Box 16, Folder 5)
  - Baylor University: Killed in Action (1 of 2), undated (Box 16, Folder 6)
  - Baylor University: Killed in Action (2 of 2), undated (Box 16, Folder 7)
  - Wings Club, 1946-1949, undated (Box 16, Folder 8)